## **GIRISH KUMAR KANNAN**

girishkumar.kannan@gmail.com +1-407-633-8501 https://www.linkedin.com/in/girish-kumar-k Citizen of India with F-1 Visa and OPT Work Permit in USA. 3065, Southern Pine Trail, Orlando, FL – 32826, USA.

#### **SUMMARY**

A Master's degree graduate encompassing a wide range of technical skills. Primarily focused towards Robotics, Automation, Mechatronics, Signal Processing, Computer Vision and applying Machine Learning concepts in related fields. Experienced in Programming Languages, Electronic Circuit Board Design and Analysis. Versatile and hardworking, passionate towards working in a team to accelerate outcome-based engineering goals. Accountable and responsible with assigned tasks. Motivated towards designing and developing quality technologies, systems and processes that further our collective interests.

### **EDUCATION**

University of Central Florida, Orlando, Florida, USA.

August 2016 - May 2018

CGPA: 3.475/4.0

## **Mater of Science in Computer Engineering**

<u>Related Coursework</u>: Advanced Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Intelligent Systems, Computer Vision, Control Systems, State Estimation, Digital Signal Processing, Adaptive DSP, Neuroscientific Systems, Modeling and Simulation.

#### Related Projects:

- Prediction and Signal Smoothening using Kalman Filter: Designed a robot that uses an algorithm developed to obtain Magnetic Heading from Digital Inertial Sensor.
- Occupancy Grid based 2D-SLAM Robot: Deployed A-Star Search and Reinforcement Learning techniques to navigate a robot
  which can Simultaneously Localize and Map a quasi-stochastic region using Occupancy Grid model.
- Multi-Detection Computer Vision: Developed a set of Computer Vision algorithms to make a webcam detect hand gestures as mouse commands and perform Optical Character Recognition as well, on a real-time basis.
- Mini-Projects in Computer Vision: Implemented and presented common Computer Vision Algorithms and Convolutional Neural Network based Image and Action Sequence Classification – all from scratch.
- Programmed and compared several Machine Learning algorithms to datasets to understand the efficiency of every algorithm.
- Designed and demonstrated various Signal Filters and Processing techniques to analyze the efficiency of each design.

SRM University, Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India.

August 2011 – May 2015

CGPA: 8.902/10.0

# **Bachelor of Technology in Mechatronics** Related Projects:

- Autonomous Robot Swarm for Goal Searching :
  - Designed a limited three-agent based swarm that uses Alpha-Beta Coordination Algorithm for Goal Searching and Convergence for applications like search and rescue and resource foraging.
  - Related Publication: "On the Estimation of Optimal Robot Heading using Savitzky-Golay and Kalman Filters", International Journal of Robotics and Automation, 2015.
- Gesture Controlled Mouse: Designed a Wireless Gesture-controlled Mouse using Inertial Sensor to aid people with limb-disabilities. Built and programmed an interface that translated hand gestures to cursor actions on a computer.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, MATLAB, C, C++, [Java, C#, SQL, HTML, R]

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux (Raspbian, Debian, Ubuntu)

Applications: OpenCV, TensorFlow, EAGLE, SolidWorks, [Simulink, LabVIEW, M/s Office, Project, Visio, Git]

Test Equipments: Multimeters, Oscilloscopes, Signal/Function Generators, Power Supplies, Precision Toolsets, Soldering.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Adjunct Professor (EET), Valencia College (West), Orlando, Florida, USA.

Aug 2018 – Present

- Teaching "Fundamentals of AC Circuits" course for Associate's Degree Students of Electrical Engineering Technology.
- Computer Engineer Intern, Parseval LLC, Orlando, Florida, USA.

Aug 2018 – Present

- Developing a project that can perform dynamic sound equalization and noise masking by altering the soundscape. Designing and developing algorithms, signal communication strategy and device communication topologies.
- DSP Engineer (Volunteer-Associate), Parseval LLC, Orlando, Florida, USA.

May 2017 – April 2018

- Developed a project that saves trapped lives in a vehicle endangered by unsafe temperatures. Procured necessary components for compact fabrication, designed circuit boards, assembled, analyzed and tested the efficacy of the design.
- Designed and programmed automated microphone stand to perceive soundscape of a room. Procured components, created CAD models and 3D printed, programmed device control, tested product design and evaluated working efficiency.
- Demonstrated and deployed several Signal Processing methods and techniques on projects.
- Researched and implemented Sound Source Localization by Arraying Microphones.